Joseph F. Ghanimah

(630) 670-7606 • jfghanimah@gmail.com • 234 S Central Ave • Wood Dale, IL 60191

www.josephghanimah.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Highly adaptable Computer Engineering major currently attending University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, with 3+ years of relevant experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of application development and advanced technology skills to successfully fill the Software Engineer role at your company. Frequently praised as focused by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, IL

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering (GPA 3.24)

August 2018 - May 2022

- Minors: Mathematical Statistics, Data Science
- Awards & Honors: President's Award Program Honors Student, College of Engineering James Scholar
- **Activities:** Illini Esports Manager & Headcoach

EXPERIENCE

College CoD League

Wood Dale, IL

Lead Developer (Collegecod.com)

- June 2018 Present • Manage DigitalOcean linux web server with Nginx and Gunicorn
- Design, deploy, and maintain website, using Python (Django), JS, CSS, and HTML
- Identify problems uncovered by testing or customer feedback, and correct problems or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction
- Develop a complex database infrastructure that supports thousands of data entries and allows for advanced statistical calculations.
- Document technical factors such as server load, bandwidth, database performance and browser and
- Track SEO and web analytics to present with internal development and design teams.

G3 Circuit L.L.C.

Urbana-Champaign, IL

Founder & Lead Developer

August 2018 - September 2019

- Lead a team of 20+, distributing company's limited resources to ensure goal of expanding competitive play to a wider audience
- Organized 300+ competitors in various matches and tournaments for league season
- Deployed a serverless web application on Google Cloud Platform to manage teams and players using Python (Flask), MySQL, HTML, CSS, and Javascript

O'Hare Freight USA Inc.

Bensenville, IL

Night Shift Security Guard

May 2017 - August 2018

- Written and verbal reports of over-night activities and irregularities of industrial premises such as equipment or property damage, theft, presence of unauthorized persons, or unusual occurrences.
- Inspect and adjust security systems and equipment to ensure operations use and to detect evidence of tampering.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Project experience with machine learning, cloud computing, automation, and data science
- Proficient in Python (Django, Flask, Tensorflow)
- Additional experience with C++, C#, SQL, Javascript, HTML, and CSS
- Experience collaborating in a small and large team environments using applications like Trello, Slack, Github, and Discord